# howardwilson

#### contact

howard@watsonbox.net

github.com/watsonbox watsonbox.github.com

#### languages

english mother tongue fluent french

#### programming

♥ Ruby / Rails Python, C++, PHP CSS3 & HTML5

## profile

Highly motivated I.T. professional, capable of integrating quickly into existing teams, applying relevant skills and technologies where appropriate. Experienced in achieving the highest standards of development, with careful appreciation of project timescales and resource. Good communication skills; confident and articulate.

### education

2001–2004 **Computer Science** BSc Hons

The University of Warwick, England

Paris, France

First Class - 80% Average.

**Freelance - Various Projects** 

Third Year Project - 89% awarded 'Project of the Year 2004'.

## **experience**

2014-Now

2014 NOW	Ember.js, Swift/iOS
2012–2014	Fanzy Paris, France Technical Team Lead / CTO
	Ruby on Rails, Amazon EC2/RDS, Elasticsearch, MongoDB, Face-book/Twitter/YouTube/Instagram APIs
2011-2012	<b>eYeka</b> Senior Developer / Technical Team Lead Ruby on Rails, Gigya Social Login/Sharing
2010-2011	<b>Smartdate</b> Senior Developer - Contract Paris, France
	Ruby on Rails 2.3, Amazon EC2, NoSQL data stores, memcached, collaborative matching, Facebook Graph API
2009-2010	Halogen Solutions LimitedParis, FranceManaging Director - Self EmployedRuby on Rails 2.2, MySQL, Linux systems administration
2008-2009	Smart Business CommunicationsParis, FranceEMEA e-Learning Project Manager - ContractPHP, MySQL, Ruby on Rails 2.1, Linux systems administration
2006-2008	RM Education Plc Didcot, Oxfordshire, UK Technical Team Lead - Contract C#, ASP.NET, COM+, Transact-SQL
2006	Sygneca Ltd Cliddesden, Hampshire, UK Web Application Developer - Contract Scala
2004-2006	<b>Dorset Software Services</b> NET/C# Consultant Analyst Programmer  Poole, Dorset, UK